本来这是一场艰难的比赛。
A priori it was a difficult match.
A priori era un partido difícil.
是的，是的，我们知道。
Yes, yes, we knew.
Sí, sí, sabíamos.
在这里比赛，到目前为止，与这个对手比赛是多么困难......
How difficult it is to play here, to play so far, to play against this rival that...
Lo difícil que es jugar acá, jugar hasta ahora, jugar contra este rival que...
非常激烈，已经打得很好一段时间了，我们知道这将是多么复杂。
very intense that has been playing very well for a while, we knew how complicated it was going to be.
muy intenso que viene jugando muy bien hace rato, sabíamos lo complicado que iba a ser.
这是犯罪吗？
Was it criminal?
¿Fue penal?
我没看到，但是听同事说...
I didn't see it, but from what my colleagues tell me that...
No la vi, pero por lo que me dicen mis compañeros que...
他们看到这并不是犯罪，但奇怪的是他们没有看到朱利安的，他们很快就会看到这个，他说得这么快。
That they saw it was not criminal, but the strange thing is that they have not seen Julián's, that they are going to see this one so quickly, what he said so quickly.
Que la vieron no fue penal, pero lo raro es que no hayan visto la de Julián, que esta la vayan a ver tan rápido, que decía tan rápido.
感觉很深，我们知道这一点
that feels a lot, we knew it
que se siente mucho, lo sabíamos
当我们训练比比赛时间晚得多时，我们知道这会很困难
When we did training much later than the time we were going to play we knew it was going to be difficult
cuando hicimos el entrenamiento mucho más tarde encima de la hora que íbamos a jugar sabíamos que iba a ser difícil
但这对我们俩来说都很困难，仅此而已。
But it was difficult for both of us, that's it.
Pero era difícil para los dos, ya está.
你必须考虑即将发生的事情。
You have to think about what's coming.
Hay que pensar en lo que viene.
哥伦比亚球员最后怎么样了？
What happened in the end with the Colombian players?
¿Qué pasó en el final con los jugadores colombianos?
有事还是无事？
Something or not?
¿Algo o no?
不，不，不。
No, no, no.
我们刚刚去...
We just went...
Solamente fuimos...
问对方为什么不去见朱利安。
to ask the other why he didn't go see Julián.
a preguntar al otro por qué no fue a verla de Julián.
阿根廷为何输球？
Why did Argentina lose?
¿Por qué perdió a Argentina?
其次，你是否认为这有犯罪行为。
And second, if it seemed criminal to you or not.
Y segundo, si te pareció penal o no.
我认为这是一场相当势均力敌的比赛。
I think it was a pretty even match.
Yo creo que fue un partido bastante parejo.
两支球队一直做得很好。
two teams that have been doing things very well.
dos selecciones que vienen haciendo las cosas muy bien.
好吧，最终是哥伦比亚。
And well, it ended up being for Colombia.
Y bueno, terminó siendo para Colombia.
我没看过比赛，我不知道，那是一个点球。
I didn't see the play, I don't know, it was a penalty.
La jugada no la vi, no sé, fue penal.
这看起来并不构成犯罪。
It didn't seem criminal.
no pareció penal.
有时他们会玩那些东西。
Sometimes they play those things.
A veces tocan esas cosas.
好吧，就是这样，你必须忍受这一点。
And well, that's it, you have to live with that.
Y bueno, ya está, hay que convivir con eso.
与此同时，我们可以找借口或者天气吗？
In the meantime, can we look for an excuse or the weather?
En el transcurso, en el mientras tanto, ¿se puede buscar alguna excusa o el clima?
它仍然是降低性能的东西。
It is still something that reduces performance.
no deja de ser algo que le disminuye el rendimiento.
它们是始终有其...的因素
They are factors that always have their...
Son factores que siempre tienen su...
它的重量，它的调味料。
its weight, its seasoning.
su peso, su condimento.
我认为为了让演出变得更好，应该在其他时间举行，但是嘿......
I think that to make the show better it should be at another time, but hey...
Creo que para hacer mejor el espectáculo debería ser en otro horario, pero bueno ya...
我们已经有点习惯这些事情了
We are a little used to these things
Estamos un poco acostumbrados a estas cosas
他们按照这个时间表带我们去了巴兰基亚。
They brought us to Barranquilla with this schedule.
Nos trajeron a Barranquilla con este horario.
当时我们要去智利玩...
At the time we had to go to Chile to play...
En su momento tuvimos que ir a Chile a jugar al...
凭借身高，每个人都试图占据优势。
with height, each one tries to take advantage.
con altura, cada uno intenta sacar su ventaja.
很正常，他们在玩...
It's normal, they are playing with...
Es normal, están jugando con...
与世界上最好的球队一起，有时候我们必须赢，就像哥伦比亚一样，我们上次必须赢，而今天我们必须输。
with the best team in the world and well sometimes we have to win like with Colombia we had to the other time and today we have to lose.
con la mejor selección del mundo y bueno a veces nos toca ganar como con Colombia nos tocó la otra vez y hoy nos toca perder.
他们习惯于获胜吗？
Are they used to winning?
¿Están acostumbrados a ganar?
你如何忍受失败？
How do you live with defeats?
¿Cómo conviven con las derrotas?
事情发生在乌拉圭吗？
Did it happen in Uruguay?
¿Pasó en Uruguay?
沙特阿拉伯也发生过这种情况吗？
Did it happen with Saudi Arabia?
¿Pasó con Arabia Saudita?
除了比赛之外，事实是，在整个旅程中我们损失很少。
Apart from the game, the truth is that throughout this journey we had to lose very little.
Aparte del juego, la verdad que en todo este recorrido nos tocó perder muy poco.
过去五年内三场比赛。
Three games in the last five years.
Tres partidos en los últimos cinco años.
正如我告诉过你的，它很小，但它是一部分，我们也是这样理解的。
It is very little and it is part, as I told you, and we understand it that way.
Es muy poquito y es parte, como te dije, y nosotros lo entendemos de esa manera.
他们在比赛中仍然比罗德里有优势，值得注意的是，他们并没有背叛自己的比赛方式，他们试图追赶他。
They still had an advantage over Rodri in the match, it was noticeable in the team that they did not betray their way of playing, they tried to go after him.
Aúnen de ventaja a Rodri en el partido, se notó en la selección que no traicionó su manera de jugar, intentó ir a buscarlo.
你认为缺少了什么？
What do you think was missing?
¿Qué crees que le faltó?
是的，我认为在我们打成1-1之后……
Yes, I think that after we had made the 1-1...
Sí, yo creo que después que habíamos hecho el 1-1...
我们表现​​得很好，点球大战刚刚发生。
We were fine and the penalty play just happened.
Estábamos bien y justo sucede la jugada del penal.
它们是变化的细节。
They are details that change.
Son detalles que cambian.
上半场我不知道胡利安的表现是否是点球。
In the first half I don't know if Julián's play was a penalty or not.
En el primer tiempo no sé la jugada de Julián si fue penal o no.
它们是细节，使
They are details that make the
son detalles que hacen al
就游戏的发展而言，就是这样，正如我之前告诉过你的，我们不得不输。
to the development of the game and that's it, we had to lose as I told you before.
al desarrollo del partido y ya está, nos tocó perder como te dije antes.
有时我们必须赢，就像上次对阵哥伦比亚时我们必须赢一样。
Sometimes we have to win like we had to win last time with Colombia.
A veces nos toca ganar como nos tocó la última vez con Colombia.
今天轮到他们了，没问题。
Today it was their turn and it's fine.
Hoy le tocó a ellos y está bien.
您对迪布受到如此多的骚扰感到惊讶吗？
Were you surprised by so much harassment against Dibu?
¿Te sorprendió tanto hostigamiento contra Dibu?
不，这不正常。
No, it's not normal.
No, no es normal.
正如我告诉过你的，这种情况正在发生，今天每个人都想击败阿根廷队。
That's happening, as I told you, today everyone wants to beat the Argentine team.
Está pasando eso, como te digo, hoy todos le quieren ganar a la selección argentina.
我认为他们没有让国歌安静下来是不好的。
I think it wasn't good that they didn't silence the anthem.
Creo que no estuvo bueno que no hayan siluado el himno.
但有时我能理解，因为...
but I understand sometimes since...
pero entiendo a veces desde...
从痛苦中解脱出来，因​​为她肯定对赢得美洲杯感到非常兴奋，而且，这是为了我们。
from pain because surely she was very excited to win the Copa América and well, it was for us.
desde el dolor porque seguramente ella tenía mucha ilusión de ganar la Copa América y bueno, fue para nosotros.
这是游戏的一部分，只要一切都保持在那里就可以了。
and it's part of the game, as long as everything stays there it's fine.
y es parte del juego, mientras todo quede ahí está bien.
他们偷走了国歌，你说，这将是勇敢的。
They stole the anthem, you said, it's going to be brave.
Se robaron el himno, dijiste, va a ser bravo.
然后他说走一步，躲了起来。
And then he said step and took cover.
Y después decía escalón y se escubó.
处罚之后，几乎什么都没有。
After the penalty, practically nothing.
Después del penal, prácticamente nada.
事实是，比赛很少，什么也没打，但是，嘿，这也是裁判的一部分。
The truth is that very little was played, nothing was played, but hey, that's part of the referee too.
Se jugó muy poquito la verdad, se jugó nada, pero bueno, eso es parte del árbitro también.
我向裁判询问了点球大战的情况，以及为什么没有继续进行。
I asked the referee about the penalty play, about why it wasn't continued being played.
Yo le pregunté al árbitro sobre la jugada del penal, sobre por qué no se seguía jugando.
他告诉了我一个有点奇怪的短语，但什么也没有，什么也没有。
He told me a slightly strange phrase, but nothing, nothing there.
Me dijo una frase un poco rara, pero nada, nada que hay.
正如我所说，游戏中发生的事情总是会保留。
Always, as I say, what happens in the game stays.
Siempre, como digo, lo que pasa en el partido queda.
在酒吧里看到的是，他对一张冻结的图像、一张照片收取了罚款，其中看到了联系人，但没有给出上下文，我不知道你是否看到了。
What was seen in the bar is that he charged the penalty for a frozen image, for a photo, in which the contact is seen but then the context is not given, I don't know if you saw that.
Lo que se vio en el bar es que cobró el penal por una imagen congelada, por una foto, que se ve el contacto pero después no hace el contexto, no sé si ustedes vieron eso.
不，伙计，我真的什么都没看到。
No, man, I really didn't see anything.
No, tío, la verdad no vi nada.
有时会有评论，他们告诉我们的家人。
Sometimes the comments come, the family that they tell us.
A veces llegan los comentarios, la familia que nos dicen.
这很奇怪，正如我也告诉过你的那样，朱莉安的，我不知道，但因为我没有看到他们，所以我不想给出太多的意见。
It was quite strange, as I also told you, Juliane's, I don't know, but since I didn't see them, I don't want to give too much of an opinion.
fue bastante rara, como te digo también la de Juliane, no sé, pero como no las vi, no quiero opinar mucho.
但毫无疑问，这使得游戏的发展。
but undoubtedly that makes the development of the game.
pero indudablemente que eso hace el desarrollo del partido.
这是比赛的一部分，我们必须输掉比赛，事实是我们是一支......
It's part of the game, we had to lose and the truth is that we are a team that...
Es parte del juego, nos tocó perder y la verdad que somos una selección que...
他不习惯这一点，这也会让我们成长。
He is not used to that and that is also going to make us grow.
no está acostumbrado a eso y también eso nos va a hacer crecer.
是的，显然，我们总是想念他，所以现在让我们希望......
Yes, obviously, we always miss him, so let's hope that now...
Sí, obvio, siempre lo extrañamos, así que esperemos que ahora...
十月他可以和我们在一起，我会让我们再次享受。
In October he can be with us and I will make us enjoy again.
en octubre pueda estar con nosotros y vuelvo a hacernos disfrutar.
每个人都想击败世界上最好的球队。
Everyone wants to beat the best team in the world.
Todos le quieren ganar a la mejor selección del mundo.
他们坐在那个位置上并以这种方式看待它。
They sit in that position and see it that way.
se sienten en esa posición y lo ven de esa manera.
让我们看看，我们已经取得了重要的成就。
Let's see, we have achieved important things.
a ver, hemos conseguido cosas importantes.
我们必须继续工作，继续成长。
We have to keep working, keep growing.
tenemos que seguir trabajando, seguir creciendo.
只有这样才能继续实现这些目标。
in the only way they can continue to be achieved.
de la única manera que se pueden seguir consiguiendo.
不要让它留在路上。
Don't let it stay on the road.
que no se quede en el camino.
就像我们在纪念碑球场上所做的那样，我们在对阵智利的比赛中踢出了一场精彩的比赛。
like we did at the Monumental, we played a great game against Chile.
como lo hicimos en el Monumental, que hemos hecho un gran partido contra Chile.
今天是一场艰难的比赛，干燥的场地、赛程、炎热的天气。
and today is a difficult game, the dry field, the schedule, the heat.
y hoy es un partido difícil, la cancha seca, el horario, el calor.
但是，嘿，我刚刚对一位同事说过，要继续成长。
But hey, I just said it to a colleague to continue growing too.
Pero bueno, lo dije recién a un colega para seguir creciendo también.
必须对这些事情进行分析，因为...
These things have to be analyzed because...
Estas cosas se tienen que analizar porque...
对于节目，对于观看的人，对于在场上的我们来说，打球都变得非常困难。
For the show, for the people watching, for us who are on the field, it becomes very difficult to play.
Para el espectáculo, para la gente que mira, para nosotros que estamos dentro de la cancha, se hace muy difícil jugar.
这次不是因为温度，而是因为田地干燥，田地条件差。
Not this time, not because of the temperature, but with the dry field, with the field in poor conditions.
No esta hora, no por la temperatura, sino con el campo seco, con el campo de malas condiciones.
它极大地损害了节目的本质、我们的游戏是什么、我们习惯做的事情。
It greatly damages what the show is, what our game is, what we are used to doing.
Perjudica mucho a lo que es el espectáculo, a lo que es nuestro juego, a lo que estamos acostumbrados a hacer.
这让他有点生气，但季后赛就是这样，你必须适应一切。
and that makes him a little angry out there, but then the playoffs are like that, you have to adapt to everything.
y eso por ahí le da un poquito de bronca, pero después las eliminatorias son así, hay que adaptarse a todo.
劳塔罗受罚了吗？
Was Lautaro penalized?
¿Lautaro fue penal?
我没看到，我实在无法告诉你。
I didn't see it, I can't really tell you.
No lo vi, realmente no te puedo decir.
他们的球员告诉我...
Their player told me that...
El jugador de ellos me dijo que...
说他们碰过他，但是，好吧，在更衣室里我们正在观看比赛，或者他们正在分析比赛，他们说博塔还没有碰过他。
that they had touched him, but well, there in the locker room we were watching or they were analyzing the play and they said that Botta had not yet.
que lo habían tocado, pero bueno, ahí en el vestuario estábamos viendo o estaban analizando la jugada y decían que Botta todavía no.
他跳下去的时候并没有碰到她。
He hadn't touched her when he jumped.
No la había tocado cuando él se tiró.
他们声称有关于朱利安的事情吗？
Do they claim one about Julián?
¿Reclaman uno sobre Julián?
他们还剩下一份关于朱利安的事情吗？
Are they left claiming one about Julián?
¿Se quedan reclamando uno sobre Julián?
是的，上半场也是如此。
Yes, that too, in the first half.
Sí, eso también, en el primer tiempo.
朱利安寻找球，守门员出来打他，然后也踩到了他。
Julián looks for the ball and the goalkeeper comes out to hit him, then steps on him too.
Julián en busca de la pelota y el arquero sale a chocarlo, después lo pisa también.
但是，嘿，在比赛情况下，裁判......
But hey, they are game situations where the referee...
Pero bueno, son situaciones de juego donde el árbitro...
他什么也没看到，我们只剩下我们所做的积极的事情和我们必须改进的消极的事情。
He didn't see anything and we are left with the positive things we did and the negative things we have to improve.
No vio nada y nos quedamos con las cosas positivas que hicimos y las negativas hay que mejorar.
当然，当他们吹响国歌时，你就会想象他们将会有一场多么勇敢的比赛。
Of course, since they whistled the anthem you imagined what a brave game they were going to have.
Claro, desde que silbaron el himno imaginabas un partido bravo que iba a tener.
由于迪布的骚扰，罚球后几乎没有比赛了。
the harassment of Dibu, after the penalty there was practically no more play.
el hostigamiento a Dibu, después del penal prácticamente no se jugó más.
我们当然知道我们会遇到这种情况，但是......
Surely we knew we were going to encounter this scenario but...
Seguramente que sabíamos que nos íbamos a encontrar con este escenario pero...
但是，是的，正如我们所说，在他们受到处罚后，比赛被缩短了。
but yes, as we say, after their penalty the game was cut short.
pero sí, como decimos, después del penal de ellos el partido se hizo cortado.
当我们停下来喝水时，会受到很多干扰，因此会稍微影响游戏的节奏。
many interruptions when we stop to drink water, so it takes away the rhythm of the game a bit.
muchas interrupciones cuando paramos a tomar agua, entonces le quita un poco el ritmo del partido.
正如我告诉你的，你必须分析我告诉你的很多关于田地、浇水、制作……的内容。
And as I tell you, you have to analyze a lot what I tell you about the fields, about watering them, about making...
Y como te digo, hay que analizar mucho lo que te digo de los campos, de regarlos, de hacer que...
对于我们这些在现场、作为主角的人以及观看它的人来说，这个节目更加流畅，比任何东西都重要。
that the show is more fluid, more than anything for us who are inside the field and are the protagonists and for the people who watch it.
que el espectáculo sea más fluido, más que nada para nosotros que estamos adentro de la cancha y somos los protagonistas y para la gente que lo mira.
哥伦比亚队的第一个进球，劳塔罗，你对此有何分析？
Colombia's first goal, what analysis did you make of that, Lautaro?
El primer gol de Colombia, ¿qué análisis hicieron de ese, Lautaro?
嗯，我想我们有点注意力不集中。
Well, we were a little unfocused, I think.
Bueno, estuvimos un poco desconcentrados, creo yo.
当他们演奏得很短时，但好吧，就这样了，现在结束了
when they played it short but well that's it, it's over now
cuando la jugaron corta pero bueno ya está ya pasó ahora
每个人都会思考...
everyone is going to think about...
cada uno va a pensar en...
他们的俱乐部，然后当我们再次聚在一起时，我们一定会分析这场比赛
in what their clubs and then when we get together again we will surely analyze this match that is
en lo que sus clubes y después cuando volvamos a juntarnos seguramente analizaremos este partido que es
我们将再次聚在一起，继续为即将到来的比赛做准备。
where we will all be together again to continue preparing for this upcoming tie.
donde ya estaremos todos juntos de nuevo para seguir preparando en esta eliminatoria que viene.
这次与朱利安在袭击中分享一对的双重约会给你留下了什么样的感受？
What feelings did this double date leave you, sharing a pair with Julián in the attack?
¿Qué sensaciones te dejó esta doble fecha compartiendo dupla con Julián en el ataque?
非常好，很好的感觉，因为我们必须分享。
Very good, nice sensations because we had to share.
Muy buena, sensaciones lindas porque nos tocó compartir.
在两场比赛中
both in both games
los dos en los dos partidos
与另一名前锋分享总是好的。
It's always good to share with another striker.
Siempre es bueno compartir con otro delantero.
谁有你的特点或者打同样的位置。
who has your characteristics or plays the same position.
que tiene tus características o juega de la misma posición.
工作是共享的，所以没有什么积极的东西，我们必须继续改进。
The work is shared, so nothing positive, we must continue improving.
el trabajo se comparte, entonces nada positivo, hay que seguir mejorando.